<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: treasury | The Blog of Marc Gayle]]></title>
  <link href="http://marcgayle.com/blog/categories/treasury/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marcgayle.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-17T16:45:09-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://marcgayle.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Marc Gayle]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where do your federal tax dollars go? [Graphic Illustration]]]></title>
    <link href="http://marcgayle.com/2009/04/18/where-do-your-federal-tax-dollars-go-graphic-illustration/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-18T00:48:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marcgayle.com/2009/04/18/where-do-your-federal-tax-dollars-go-graphic-illustration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.wallstats.com/" title="Wall Stats" target="_blank">Wallstats.com</a> has a nice graphic that illustrates the federal budget and how taxes are spent. It also shows, quite nicely, the <strong>gap</strong> between what the government makes and what the government spends - which has to be borrowed - otherwise known as the budget deficit (see the bottom right-side of the graphic).</p>

<p>[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="500" caption="What is money? by Kevin Dooley"]<div class="p_embed p_image_embed">
<img alt="Media_httpfarm2static_yuxbv" height="196" src="http://marcgayle.com/images/2009/04/18/where-do-your-federal-tax-dollars-go-graphic-illustration/11605976-media_httpfarm2static_yuxBv.jpg" width="500">
</div>
[/caption]</p>

<p> </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unprecedented Transparency from the Treasury]]></title>
    <link href="http://marcgayle.com/2009/04/01/unprecedented-transparency-from-the-treasury-1/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-01T05:49:36-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marcgayle.com/2009/04/01/unprecedented-transparency-from-the-treasury-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a day and age when confidence is shaken by the daily doldrums of the markets, and a bullish day is <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123854930706576507.html" title="WSJ.com - What to do if you blink and miss the market rally." target="_blank">celebrated as some form of stimulus bill</a>, the recent actions by the Treasury and the Obama administration are welcomed. The treasury announced the launch of a website - <a href="http://financialstability.gov/index.html" title="Treasury Website to Track Financial Transactions" target="_blank">FinancialStability.gov</a> - where they have started to provided unprecendented transparency into the financial transactions conducted by the government on the road to stabilizing the financial system.<!--more--></p>

<p>For starters, they list all the money doled out as of March, 2009, through the $700B Trouble Asset Relief Program Act passed by congress last year. They specify not only which financial institutions receive the funds - but also how much they got, the date of the transaction, etc. They even included a <a href="http://financialstability.gov/impact/index.html" title="Local Impact of the Capital Purchase Program" target="_blank">nice interactive map of the United States</a> that makes it easy to understand.</p>

<p>For the more 'detail-hungry' among us, that prefer more arcane documents with all the nitty-gritty financial gobblygoop, they have also released <a href="http://financialstability.gov/latest/reportsanddocs.html" title="Financial Stability - Reports &amp; Documents" target="_blank">transaction reports, section 105 reports to congress about the TARP program, Tranche Reports and more</a>. Not satisfied ? Want to see the actual documents/contracts signed between each individual TARP recipient and Treasury, including signatures? No problem, <a href="http://financialstability.gov/impact/contracts_list.htm" title="Treasury - List of Signed Contracts with TARP Recipients" target="_blank">they even have a menu item for you too</a>. Don't believe me? Look at the <a href="http://financialstability.gov/docs/agreements/JPMorgan_Chase_Agreement_Dated_26_October_2008.pdf" title="Treasury - JPMorgan Chase signed TARP contract" target="_blank">agreement with JPMorgan Chase</a> for yourself.</p>

<p>Please, dig in and find some interesting stuff. Post it in the comments and I will update this post. I know that when I get some time, I most definitely will.</p>

<p>If I were to see Timothy Geithner tomorrow, I would first congratulate him on the outstanding job of opening up these documents to the public and making them easily accessible - not just accessible. The second thing I would do is ask him, 'why did you guys spend $15.5M in Jan. 2009 on 'Non-Personnel Expenses' and $37.6M in Feb. 2009 on the same line item for TARP Administration (<a href="http://financialstability.gov/docs/105aReport_02032009.pdf" title="Section 105 Congressional Report for Feb.03.2009" target="_blank">see Section 105 Congressional Report for Feb. 03, 2009</a> - page 7 of 16)?'. Also, what on earth are 'Other Services' - that seems to be the bulk of the 'Non-Personnel Expenses'.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
