<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Geithner | The Blog of Marc Gayle]]></title>
  <link href="http://marcgayle.com/blog/categories/geithner/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marcgayle.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-17T16:45:09-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://marcgayle.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Marc Gayle]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unprecedented Transparency from the Treasury]]></title>
    <link href="http://marcgayle.com/2009/04/01/unprecedented-transparency-from-the-treasury-1/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-01T05:49:36-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marcgayle.com/2009/04/01/unprecedented-transparency-from-the-treasury-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a day and age when confidence is shaken by the daily doldrums of the markets, and a bullish day is <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123854930706576507.html" title="WSJ.com - What to do if you blink and miss the market rally." target="_blank">celebrated as some form of stimulus bill</a>, the recent actions by the Treasury and the Obama administration are welcomed. The treasury announced the launch of a website - <a href="http://financialstability.gov/index.html" title="Treasury Website to Track Financial Transactions" target="_blank">FinancialStability.gov</a> - where they have started to provided unprecendented transparency into the financial transactions conducted by the government on the road to stabilizing the financial system.<!--more--></p>

<p>For starters, they list all the money doled out as of March, 2009, through the $700B Trouble Asset Relief Program Act passed by congress last year. They specify not only which financial institutions receive the funds - but also how much they got, the date of the transaction, etc. They even included a <a href="http://financialstability.gov/impact/index.html" title="Local Impact of the Capital Purchase Program" target="_blank">nice interactive map of the United States</a> that makes it easy to understand.</p>

<p>For the more 'detail-hungry' among us, that prefer more arcane documents with all the nitty-gritty financial gobblygoop, they have also released <a href="http://financialstability.gov/latest/reportsanddocs.html" title="Financial Stability - Reports &amp; Documents" target="_blank">transaction reports, section 105 reports to congress about the TARP program, Tranche Reports and more</a>. Not satisfied ? Want to see the actual documents/contracts signed between each individual TARP recipient and Treasury, including signatures? No problem, <a href="http://financialstability.gov/impact/contracts_list.htm" title="Treasury - List of Signed Contracts with TARP Recipients" target="_blank">they even have a menu item for you too</a>. Don't believe me? Look at the <a href="http://financialstability.gov/docs/agreements/JPMorgan_Chase_Agreement_Dated_26_October_2008.pdf" title="Treasury - JPMorgan Chase signed TARP contract" target="_blank">agreement with JPMorgan Chase</a> for yourself.</p>

<p>Please, dig in and find some interesting stuff. Post it in the comments and I will update this post. I know that when I get some time, I most definitely will.</p>

<p>If I were to see Timothy Geithner tomorrow, I would first congratulate him on the outstanding job of opening up these documents to the public and making them easily accessible - not just accessible. The second thing I would do is ask him, 'why did you guys spend $15.5M in Jan. 2009 on 'Non-Personnel Expenses' and $37.6M in Feb. 2009 on the same line item for TARP Administration (<a href="http://financialstability.gov/docs/105aReport_02032009.pdf" title="Section 105 Congressional Report for Feb.03.2009" target="_blank">see Section 105 Congressional Report for Feb. 03, 2009</a> - page 7 of 16)?'. Also, what on earth are 'Other Services' - that seems to be the bulk of the 'Non-Personnel Expenses'.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geithner, Summers & Bernanke - A Performance to Remember?]]></title>
    <link href="http://marcgayle.com/2009/03/28/geithner-bernanke-performance_review-1/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-28T06:00:45-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marcgayle.com/2009/03/28/geithner-bernanke-performance_review-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> </p>

<p>[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="453" caption="Summers, Bair, Bernanke &amp; Geithner (Credit: Cleveland.com)"]<div class="p_embed p_image_embed">
<img alt="Media_httpblogclevela_dxkba" height="314" src="http://marcgayle.com/images/2009/03/28/geithner-bernanke-performance_review-1/16930071-media_httpblogclevela_DxkbA.jpg" width="453">
</div>
[/caption]</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The latest craze has been for us to look for someone to blame. Perhaps times are so stressful that people need to vent. Perhaps the problems are so big that someone needs to be villified. Perhaps things are so miserable that we need company. Perhaps. Who knows. But people are getting blamed. </p>

<p>When Henry Paulson was the man @ the wheels of steel, <a href="http://www.politicker.com/arizona/1903/shadegg-calls-paulson-resignation" title="Paulson Resignation" target="_blank">people weren't too pleased with him</a>. Many have <a href="http://www.politico.com/blogs/glennthrush/0309/Issa_to_call_for_Geithners_resignation.html" title="Geithner Resignation" target="_blank">called</a> for the <a href="http://thepage.time.com/rep-mack-calls-for-geithner-to-resign-or-be-fired/?xid=rss-page" title="Geithner Resignation" target="_blank">resignation</a> of Timothy Geithner. Others have suggested that even though Larry Summers is a brilliant man, his ideas are <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/arianna-huffington/larry-summers-brilliant-m_b_178956.html" title="Larry Summers Tired Ideas" target="_blank">worn out/tired</a>. So far President Obama has stated that he <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/topNews/idUSN1838682720090322?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=topNews" title="Obama wouldn't accept Geithner's Resignation" target="_blank">would not accept</a> Geithner's resignation if it were tendered and that he is confident in the competence of his economics team. </p>

<p>Sometimes we have to take a step back from our current situation and try to look at things as objectively as we can. So, to start that process, let's go back to the beginning.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.nber.org/dec2008.html" title="Recession started December 2007" target="_blank">According to the NBER (National Bureau of Economic Research)</a> the recession officially started in December, 2007, we - 'Joe public' - never saw the indications of this crisis until March, 2008. Yes, it was years in the making, and there are many things that contributed to it - enough for a series of posts - but the current crisis got a spark in March, 2008 when word started to spread that Bear Stearns had liquidity problems. Then, suddenly, it was announced that JPMorgan was purchasing Bear for an <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/17/business/17bear.html" title="JPMorgan buying Bear Stearns for $2/share" target="_blank">underwhelming $2/share</a> in a deal put together by the Fed &amp; Treasury over the weekend. Shocks were sent through the entire financial system. Hindsight is always 20/20, so now looking back it is easy to <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/09/21/business/20cnd-wall.html" title="Bear Stearns profits down 61% on subprime woes" target="_blank">see the signs</a>. But in the moment, it wasn't.</p>

<p>Then came Fannie &amp; Freddie, Lehman Brothers, AIG &amp; the restructuring of all investment banks to 'Bank Holding' companies, within months of each other. Shortly after that, we had a string of capital injections to many (if not all) of the major banks and other financial institutions.  Then Obama won, and the transition from Paulson to Geithner &amp; Summers began. That's where the story begins.</p>

<p>It's been exactly 2 months + 1 day since Giethner has been confirmed Secretary of the Treasury. Up until March 10th, 2009 - <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2009/03/09/AR2009030902807.html" title="Every key position in Treasury Vacant" target="_blank">according to the Washington Post</a> - every single 'key position' within the Treasury (aside from Secretary) has remained vacant. Obama <a href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/ap/article/ALeqM5iFq5mQwD2WgvSNoX3BqKSSD_yw_AD9742IA80" title="Three new players on Treasury Team" target="_blank">appointed three additional people at Treasury</a> on March 23rd, 2009, and there are still positions left to be filled as of this writing. With his skeleton crew, he has <a href="http://www.treas.gov/press/releases/reports/ppip_fact_sheet.pdf" title="Treasury PPIP Fact Sheet" target="_blank">done the following</a>:</p>

<ul>
<li>
<a href="http://www.makinghomeaffordable.gov/" title="Making Home Affordable" target="_blank">Developed and rolled out a program</a> that allows 'responsible' home owners that have mortgages currently underwater to re-finance at a lower fixed rate.</li>
    <li>Expanded TALF - Term Asset-Backed Securities Loan Facility - to <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/s/ap/20090316/ap_on_go_pr_wh/obama_economy" title="$15B to small business loans" target="_blank">unlock secondary markets for small business loans</a>. Essentially providing a much needed $15B liquidity injection to assist small businesses get access to more credit. </li>
    <li>Revised tax code to allow small businesses, with revenue up $15M, <a href="http://firstread.msnbc.msn.com/archive/2009/03/16/1838761.aspx" title="Extend Carry Loss Back Tax Benefit" target="_blank">to carry back losses 5 years - as opposed to the normal 2 years</a>. </li>
    <li>A <a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/economics/2009/02/25/bank-stress-test-faq/" title="Stress Test for Banks" target="_blank">'stress-test' for banks</a> and other large financial institutions.</li>
    <li>Designed and outlined the <a href="http://www.treas.gov/press/releases/tg65.htm" title="Treasury Plan to unlock credit markets" target="_blank">program intended to unlock the credit markets</a> by removing the 'toxic assets' from the balance sheets of large financial institutions. </li>
    <li>Outlined the <a href="http://www.treas.gov/press/releases/tg72.htm" title="Treasury - Regulatory Overhaul" target="_blank">framework for a massive regulatory overhaul</a>. </li>
</ul>


<p>Keep in mind this is all within 2 months. Now I know that there have been <a href="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e4c56948-1946-11de-9d34-0000779fd2ac.html" title="Dollar dips on Geithner misspeak" target="_blank">bumps along the way</a>, and policies haven't been rolled out as quickly as people would like them to. But it is imperative that we take a step back and look at what has been accomplished to-date.</p>

<p>Whether or not history will look back and give Geithner, Summers &amp; Bernanke all 'As' for the way they have handled this crisis is still yet to be seen. But given that the crisis still has not fully played out, and the output of the team so far speaks for itself, I would tend to err on the side of reserving - rather than passing - judgement like current mass hysteria seems to suggest.</p>

<p>If I have left out any details, please leave in comments and I will update post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
