<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | The Blog of Marc Gayle]]></title>
  <link href="http://marcgayle.com/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marcgayle.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-02T20:27:58-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://marcgayle.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Marc Gayle]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[marc.gayle+blog@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fail early, fail fast explained]]></title>
    <link href="http://marcgayle.com/2010/06/03/fail-early-fail-fast-explained/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-03T23:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marcgayle.com/2010/06/03/fail-early-fail-fast-explained</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many people misunderstand the true meaning behind 'fail early, fail fast'. The most 'high-profile' of which is <a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/1643-failure-is-overrated-a-redux" title="Failure is overated" target="_blank">Jason Fried</a> and our friends at <a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2059-podcast-episode-4-jason-frieds-speech-at-big-omaha-2009" title="37 Signals Podcast discussing fail early fail often" target="_blank">37Signals</a>.</p>


<p>Fail early, fail fast isn't encouraging you to fail. It's encouraging you to act/move/start.</p>


<p>Read the phrase again, with emphasis: fail <strong>early</strong>, fail <strong>fast</strong>.</p>


<p>The idea behind the saying is, just do something. It's easy to get trapped in a 'secure' situation. Whether that is a 'stable/cushy' job, or using a product that is OK. It's this inertia that kills innovation. It's fear of the unknown or fear of the failure that also dis-incentivizes people from striking out and making that killer product they have always envisioned, or recorded that song they have written, or sold that painting they have stashed away in their basement.</p>


<p>People get accustomed to procrastinating and delaying that they don't attempt to do what they say they want to do.</p>


<p>The phrase 'fail early, fail fast' is attempting to take the sting out of the fear of failing - by using the terms 'early' &amp; 'fast'. Makes it sound 'quick' and 'painless'. Ever been to a doctor to get an injection?</p>


<p>'It will feel like a mosquito bite' is what I am always told.</p>


<p>It's kinda like that - especially since creating a new product is so hard, the last thing a creator needs is the fear of failure hanging over their heads (although, to be fair that fear can be a good motivator).</p>


<p>I am not advocating failure, but anything that removes one more psychological barrier for inventors can only be good for society.</p>


<p>So, go ahead and fail as quickly as you can. Pick yourself up, and try again.</p>


<p><em>Editor's Note: Please note that I am not encouraging people to strike out in an attempt to fail. Simply to not be afraid of failing - if that wasn't clear enough in the post.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Google Job Experiment]]></title>
    <link href="http://marcgayle.com/2010/05/13/the-google-job-experiment/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-13T03:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marcgayle.com/2010/05/13/the-google-job-experiment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is pretty ingenius.  If I were hiring a creative guy, I would definitely hire this guy. </p>


<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/7FRwCs99DWg?wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen frameborder="0" height="417" width="500"></iframe></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The sheer power of the US Military]]></title>
    <link href="http://marcgayle.com/2010/05/13/the-sheer-power-of-the-us-military/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-13T02:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marcgayle.com/2010/05/13/the-sheer-power-of-the-us-military</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p></p>


<div class="p_embed p_image_embed">
<img alt="F16" height="375" src="http://marcgayle.com/images/2010/05/13/the-sheer-power-of-the-us-military/16960817-F16.jpg" width="500">
</div>




<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nostri-imago/2888359817/"></a>We all know that the US military is powerful, but I think it is easy to underestimate exactly how powerful they really are.  US Secretary of Defense Robert Gates was recently giving a speech at the Eisenhower Library on the 65th anniversary of the allied victory in Europe. He was pitching the case for cutting down the size of the defense budget, and addressing the concerns of many that America will lose it's strength if defense spending is overhauled. He was quite confident that that wasn't the case. Here is a choice excerpt (note, I added the emphasis):</p>


<blockquote>Finally, this Department’s approach to requirements must change.  Before making claims of requirements not being met or alleged “gaps” – in ships, tactical fighters, personnel, or anything else – we need to evaluate the criteria upon which requirements are based and the wider real world context.  For example, should we really be up in arms over a temporary projected shortfall of about 100 Navy and Marine strike fighters relative to the number of carrier wings, when America’s military possesses more than 3,200 tactical combat aircraft of all kinds? Does the number of warships we have and are building really put America at risk <strong>when the U.S. battle fleet is larger than the next 13 navies combined, 11 of which belong to allies and partners</strong>?  <strong>Is it a dire threat that by 2020 the United States will have only 20 times more advanced stealth fighters than China</strong>?</blockquote>


<p>I am a military geek, so these numbers didn't entirely startle me, but it did give me pause.  To read the entire speech, <a href="http://www.defense.gov/speeches/speech.aspx?speechid=1467" title="Robert Gates Speech at Eisenhower Library" target="_blank">check it out here</a>.  Upon reading this speech, it reminded me of an article that The Economist published some time ago. Choice excerpts are as follows:</p>


<blockquote class="posterous_medium_quote">THE Perseus, a 900kg (2,000lb) bomb made in Greece, incinerates almost everything in an area larger than a dozen football fields. Farther out, oxygen is sucked from the air and people may be crushed by a pressure wave. The inferno is similar to that caused by napalm—a jellied-petrol explosive heavily restricted by a United Nations weapons convention.</blockquote>


<p>That was just the prelude. Here is a much more impressive excerpt:</p>


<blockquote>
<div>On April 2nd 2003, during the second Gulf war, a hundred or so Iraqi armoured vehicles approached a far smaller American reconnaissance unit south of Baghdad. Responding to a call for help, a B-52 bomber attacked the first 30 or so vehicles in the column with a single, historic pass. It dropped two new CBU-105 bombs, and the result shocked the soldiers of both sides—and, soon enough, military observers everywhere.</div>
<p></p>
<div>While falling, the CBU-105 bombs popped open, each releasing ten submunitions which were slowed by parachutes. Each of these used mini rockets to spin and eject outward four discs the size of ice-hockey pucks.</div>
<div>The 80 free-falling discs from the pair of bombs then scanned the ground with lasers and heat-detecting infra-red sensors to locate armoured vehicles. Those discs that identified a target exploded dozens of metres up. The blast propelled a tangerine-sized slug of copper down into the target, destroying it with the impact and the accompanying shrapnel. The soldiers in the 70 vehicles farther back in the column surrendered immediately.</div>
</blockquote>


<div>If I were in those vehicles with the Iraqi soldiers, I would most definitely surrender after witnessing that.</div>


<p></p>


<div>The economist <a href="http://www.economist.com/sciencetechnology/displaystory.cfm?story_id=15391218" title="Advanced Ordnance - The Economist" target="_blank">article can be found here</a> (but is only available to subscribers).</div>


<p></p>


<div>P.S. Image courtesy of cliff1066 on <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nostri-imago/2888359817/" title="F-14 Tomcat" target="_blank">Flickr</a>.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Afghanistan in April 2010 in Photos]]></title>
    <link href="http://marcgayle.com/2010/05/12/afghanistan-in-april-2010-in-photos/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-12T02:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marcgayle.com/2010/05/12/afghanistan-in-april-2010-in-photos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.boston.com/bigpicture/" title="Boston Big Picture - Photo Journalism at it's best" target="_blank" style="color: #5f5f5f;"><div class="p_embed p_image_embed">
<img alt="Afghan-1" height="333" src="http://marcgayle.com/images/2010/05/12/afghanistan-in-april-2010-in-photos/16960855-afghan-1.jpg" width="500">
</div>
Boston Big Picture</a> has the best photo journal I have ever come across. It is one of the many reasons I love the internet, technology and photography. At no other time in history, could I sit 5,000 miles away from a place and see such rich representations in such a timely manner – almost instantly nowadays.</p>


<p>They recently published, essentially, the state of Afghanistan in April 2010 in Pictures. Below you will find some of my favorites.</p>


<p> </p>


<p></p>


<div class="p_embed p_image_embed">
<img alt="Afghan-5" height="316" src="http://marcgayle.com/images/2010/05/12/afghanistan-in-april-2010-in-photos/16960850-afghan-5.jpg" width="500">
<img alt="Afghan-4" height="345" src="http://marcgayle.com/images/2010/05/12/afghanistan-in-april-2010-in-photos/16960852-afghan-4.jpg" width="500">
<img alt="Afghan-3" height="330" src="http://marcgayle.com/images/2010/05/12/afghanistan-in-april-2010-in-photos/16960853-afghan-3.jpg" width="500">
<img alt="Afghan-2" height="330" src="http://marcgayle.com/images/2010/05/12/afghanistan-in-april-2010-in-photos/16960854-afghan-2.jpg" width="500">
<img alt="Afghan-6" height="327" src="http://marcgayle.com/images/2010/05/12/afghanistan-in-april-2010-in-photos/16960861-afghan-6.jpg" width="500">
</div>




<p style="font-family: Palatino, Georgia, Baskerville, serif; font-size: 14px; color: #666666; line-height: 18px;">Have I mentioned how much I love Boston Big Picture? The truth is, I saw the name of their latest article and didn’t even see the pictures, but I knew I had to write a post about it. They are always that awesome, that I never pre-screened it and picked the images as I went along. I had to restrain myself from including more from the post, because there are so many awesome ones.</p>


<p style="font-family: Palatino, Georgia, Baskerville, serif; font-size: 14px; color: #666666; line-height: 18px;">Do yourself a favor, <a href="http://www.boston.com/bigpicture/2010/05/afghanistan_april_2010.html" title="Boston Big Picture: Afghanistan April 2010" target="_blank" style="color: #5f5f5f;">go and check it out</a>, you will thank me later.</p>


<p> </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Change my credit card can believe in? You Betcha!]]></title>
    <link href="http://marcgayle.com/2010/04/15/change-my-credit-card-can-believe-in/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-15T22:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marcgayle.com/2010/04/15/change-my-credit-card-can-believe-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p></p>


<div class="p_embed p_image_embed">
<img alt="Credit-cards-1" height="375" src="http://marcgayle.com/images/2010/04/15/change-my-credit-card-can-believe-in/16966793-credit-cards-1.jpg" width="500">
</div>


<p>Sometimes it is easy for us to get sidetracked by the ‘larger’ challenges that Obama is tackling, that we miss the little things before our very eyes. Americans won’t see the effects of health care reform for another few years, easily. The same would apply to financial reform and a carbon cap/trade/credit law.</p>

<p>However, there is a <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2009/05/credit_card_legislation_become.html" title="Credit Card Legislation" target="_blank">little bill that was passed in May 2009</a> that I, personally, have directly seen the effects of. </p>


<p>Below is one of my credit card statements as of February 2010:</p>


<p></p>


<div class="p_embed p_image_embed">
<img alt="Credit-card-feb-2010" height="165" src="http://marcgayle.com/images/2010/04/15/change-my-credit-card-can-believe-in/16966791-Credit-Card-Feb-2010.png" width="500">
</div>


<p>Nothing majorly significant. All it shows is previous balance, summary of payments or purchases, finance charges minimum payment, etc. I grayed out information that could possibly be used for nefarious purposes (not you wonderful people reading my blog…the other dishonest people on the interwebs).</p>

<p>Contrast that with my statement from March 2010:</p>


<p></p>


<div class="p_embed p_image_embed">
<img alt="Credit-card-march-2010" height="309" src="http://marcgayle.com/images/2010/04/15/change-my-credit-card-can-believe-in/16966790-Credit-Card-March-2010.png" width="500">
</div>




<p>March is COMPLETELY different. Breaking down how much I will pay total if I stick with the minimum payment or if I paid a higher amount. It doesn’t matter much to me, because I always pay more than my minimum, but it just jumps out at you how much you are paying in interest.</p>


<p>That, is change I can believe in!</p>


<p>P.S. Image 1 courtesy of Andres Rueda on <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andresrueda/3027534098/" target="_blank">Flickr</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
