<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: new-product, | The Blog of Marc Gayle]]></title>
  <link href="http://marcgayle.com/blog/categories/new-product/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marcgayle.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-09T14:10:31-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://marcgayle.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Marc Gayle]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[marc.gayle+blog@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call to arms for all bloggers product launch upcoming]]></title>
    <link href="http://marcgayle.com/2013/12/09/call-to-arms-for-all-bloggers-product-launch-upcoming/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-09T13:17:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marcgayle.com/2013/12/09/call-to-arms-for-all-bloggers-product-launch-upcoming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a product launch coming up, and would love as much New Media help as I can get.</p>

<p>We will be doing a lot of traditional PR, but I feel like this would be a wikid opportunity for the Caribbean new media scene to support one of their own.</p>

<p>To let me know you are interested, email me at marc.gayle+launch@gmail.com.</p>

<p>In terms of help, I would love at least 1 article from anyone that runs a blog - with a link to the product page when it launches.</p>

<p>I can get you content or an angle to write up, customized for your audience (if you know what your audience is).</p>

<p>The first easy step you can do for me is to retweet <a href="https://twitter.com/marcgayle/status/410100571878981632">this tweet</a>.</p>

<p>Not only do I need your actual blogging help, but if you can pass along this message to anyone else you know that has a blog, tweets, IGs, anything to do with New/Social Media.</p>

<p>We will have lots of stuff to retweet, post on IG, content for blogs of all types, the whole nine yards. So if you have a blog, a twitter account, an IG account, FB or any other type of "Social Media" account and are interested in helping with the launch, please get in touch at marc.gayle+launch@gmail.com.</p>

<p>I am trying to pull off a Tim Ferris - 4 Hour Workweek Book launch - where there was so much groundswell from new media that traditional media couldn't ignore him.</p>

<p>Look forward to any (and all assistance) I can get from you guys.</p>

<p>P.S. This will be a digital fitness product that anyone with a credit card from anywhere can buy - we are going after the "New Years Resolutions" storyline and "losing weight in the New Year", etc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
